ROBMERCIER WEB DEVELOPER

LAMP stack development, database and business rules integration, front-end development, CMS integration, API programming & integration

About Me



I've been a musician, a teacher, an email marketer, a photographer, a hockey player, and a web app

I had done some programming as a kid, working in BASIC at the beginning, then as one of the primary site builders and maintainers for the bands I was in, I got into the HTML/CSS advances of the early 2000's.

I took C++ and Pascal courses in my college days, and I'm now using PHP, HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript/JQuery, and whatever frameworks work for the project.

I recently switched back to Mac from Ubuntu, which I used from v13.04 through 14.10. Overall, the experience is just a little tighter, especially on the newest version of Mac OS X (Yosemite).

linkedin.com/robmercier twitter.com/rmerc00 github.com/robmercier flickr.com/quitarsonqs00

rob.mercier00@gmail.com

Experience

Web Developer Pure Incubation

July 2014 - Present Topsfield, MA

Full LAMP stack development for user-facing public web applications, as well as administration consoles and dashboards, API integration with 3rd-party CMS & ESP (Email Service Provider) systems

Key technologies include PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript/JQuery/AJAX, XML, Selenium WebDriver, as well as numerous other free & open source tools

Junior Developer Pure Incubation

July 2013 - July 2014 Topsfield, MA

Full LAMP stack development for user-facing public web applications, as well as administration consoles and dashboards

Key technologies include PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript/JQuery/AJAX, XML, Selenium WebDriver, and various free & open source tools

Content & Social Marketing Manager Pure Incubation

June 2011 - July 2013 Topsfield, MA

Campaign planning, content selection, and production of daily e-newsletters

Building brand, membership, network opportunities, and other programs supporting the growth of Pure Incubation online communities in the companies' vertical markets

Marketing to online member audiences to grow community, foster ongoing relationships, and create a positive member user experience

Community Specialist Sermo

January 2011 – June 2011 Cambridge, MA

Coordinate and execute email marketing programs to physician community

Develop, track, and report performance measurements for community moderation and support

Take in and resolve incoming day-to-day email and phone support requests from members of the physician community

Stay connected to member satisfaction levels. Proactively work with the necessary departments to improve overall satisfaction

Associate Manager of Lead Generation Programs Ziff Davis Enterprise

April 2008 - December 2010 Topsfield, MA

Lead Generation

Created & edited content for business-to-business marketing newsletters

Created & edited HTML & text templates for newsletters

Designed newsletter/Website functionality that immediately increased lead conversions by 50%

E-mail Marketing

Implemented global redesign of all Web Buyer's Guide newsletters

Created new design for 4 additional Web Buyer's Guide newsletters

Improved IP sender reputation for Web Buyer's Guide brand newsletters to an average of 95%

Maintained exceptionally low spam/abuse complaint levels for Web Buyer's Guide newsletters

Social Media

Increased Web Buyer's Guide Twitter followers by approximately 32% per month

Implemented plan to increase Web Buyer's Guide presence across various social media networks

Implemented social media marketing along with newsletter marketing initiatives

Utilized various tracking and social marketing tools to further Web Buyer's Guide lead generation and demand generation initiatives

Owner, Instructor All4Strings

January 2003 - April 2008 Woburn, MA

Instruct students in electric and acoustic guitar, music theory, audio recording

Provide sound reinforcement for a number of bands and/or live music venues

Provide audio recording for a number of bands

Responsible for all business activities, including marketing, invoicing, accounting, Website design and maintenance

Provide a yearly student recital, including booking the recital hall, providing all sound reinforcement equipment and services and setting up post-recital reception

Live Sound Engineer Skybar

March 2006 - September 2007 Somerville, MA

Assistant Manager FYE

November 2005 – April 2006 *Medford, MA*

Head Technician Alactronics

September 2000 – December 2002 Wellesley, MA

Assistant Manager Record Town/Tape World

May 1994 - September 1999 Nashua, NH

Education

University of Massachuestts-Lowell - 2000

Bachelor of Music - Sound Recording Technology Cum Laude

President - Audio Engineering Society Student Chapter